Guide to the George B. Dantzig Papers
Stanford University Libraries.
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-2010-101
  - 145, 28633 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 146, April 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 147, 9/81 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 148, 9/81 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reminscences about the origin of LP, 9/81 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 149 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 150 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 151 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 152 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 153 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 154, March 1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 156 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 156, August 1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 157 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 158, November 1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 159 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 160, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 161 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 162, June 1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 163 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - The New Palgrave - "Linear Programming" article 164 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 165 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - 167, Apil 1986 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 166, Janurary 1987 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Not labeled (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 167 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - 168 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - 169 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - 170, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - 171, February 1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - 171 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - 172, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - 173, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - 174, June 1988 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - 175, September 1988 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - 176, December 1987 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - 177 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - 178 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - 179 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - 180 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - 181 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - 182, March 1991 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - 183 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - 184, August 1991 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - 185, 34624 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - 186 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - 187 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - 188 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - 189 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - 190 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - 191 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - 192 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - 193 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - 194 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - 195 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-2012-034
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-2012-065
  - COMP - The Dawn of Consciousness by George B. Dantzig, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - COMP In Our Own Image - a Compute Science Odyssey by George B. Dantzig, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Comp In Our Own Image by George B. Dantzig, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - From the Present (Master File of :In Our Own Image"), 1986 March 26 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Book Drawings, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter to Jenneifer Love, 2002 March 23 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Mansfield B. Frazier, 1996 March 25 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter to Cynthia Kerrey, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter from Saul I. Gass, 1982 Sept. 12 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "In Our Own Image" Teaser Summary, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter from karinna H. de Jesus, 1986 Feb. 20 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter to Fred Murphy, 1986 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter to Saul I. Gass, 1982 Aug. 6 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letter from John Suatry, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter from Floyd J. Gould, 1986 March 19 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letter from Larry Nazareth, 1986 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Various Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Advertisment for "The Dawn of Consiousness", undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Serendipity, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Various Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter to Published Fred M. Murphy, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Book; Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Murphy - Book, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Book Agreement, 1985 Aug.-Sept. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Images: Communication Notes, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "In Our Own Image" by George B. Dantzig, 1984 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Pulled Chapters, 1985 Dec. 10 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - New York Times Article, 1993 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letter from Avi Jirschenbaum, 1990 Oct. 1 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Before the Flood Chapter 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - In Our Own Image Correspondence GBD, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-2012-067
  - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Graph and Notes on Data Analysis, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bert hackney, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Proposed Extension of the Study of Decomposition Techniques for Transportation Network Analysis, 1975 Oct 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Polyplex Aglorithm-Robert F. Hauck, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Printed Slides for Various Presentations, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Application for a Canada Council Killam Research Fellowship, 1994 Jun 17 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence w/ Manuscripts Attached, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Linear and Integer Programming - Theory and Practice Interger Prog. Examples, 1995 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Uriel G. Rothblum, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondences, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - George B. Dantzig-Exams, 1991 Autumn (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Grant for Frieda Granot, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - John M. Preschon, 1992 July (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Model Formulation Suggestions, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Proposal for Integrated Model for Optimizing Equipment for a Production Line, 1992 Jan. 1-Dec. 31 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Referee's reports and Associate Editor's Reports in Regards to "Large-Scale Stochastic Linear Programs", 1992 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Multiple reports by George B. Dantzig and Colleagues - with notes, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Notes for Planning Under Uncertainty, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Notes and Data on Linear Programs, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis (IIASA), 1961-1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Micahel Saunders, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Recommendations for Gerd Infanger, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - BQA Performance Figures, 1993 Apr 27 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Planning Under Uncertainty Talk, 1998 Aug 10-17 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Institute for Planning Under Uncertainty-Incorporation Legal, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Transparencies and Presentations, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1991-1999 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Addresses and Trip Record, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Yinyu Ye and George Dantzig: A Build-Up Interior Method for Linear Programming, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Nouv O. Zaghi, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Lecture Notes, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Workshop, 1999 July 12-16 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - George B. Dantzig vs. Stanford University Age Discrimination Case, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1970-2001 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - George B. Dantzig Salary Cards, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - General Power of Attorney for George B. Dantzig, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Legal Matters, 2000 Nov. 7 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Orms Today Magazine and Other Articles of G. Dantzig, 1950s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Binder Contents of Work of Dantzig, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Review for "The Finite Element & Linear Programming Method" by Tanehiro Futagami, 1976 Dec 8 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Stanford Statistics Vol. 8, 1990 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Dantzig's Personal Notebook and Emergency Contact Info, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Final Exam of Georg B. Dantzig for Degree of Doctor of Philosophy, 1946 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Existence therorem Pertaining to Neyman-Pearson Lemma, Type A and Similar Regions, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-2013-072
  - Notes
    - Rainich (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Contains two notebooks; loose-leaf notes on theory of functions.
    - Discrimination Tests, 1939-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Contains personal correspondence; Math 261 notes; tables, "The Use of Multiple Measurements in Taxonomic Problems".
    - Notes on the Morley Trisector Configuration (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Contains notes; introduction; diagrams; proof; properties of configuration; Desargues theorem.
    - Michigan, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Contains examination booklet from algebraic theory course; notes.
    - California Notes, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Contains notes and examinations from doctorate years at University of California: Berkeley.
    - Theory of Ideals, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Contains problem sets and examinations from doctorate years at University of California: Berkeley.
    - Worksheets on inequalities. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Misc. Ideas (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Contains hand-written notes, including a section on variance; letters, graphs, and final examinations.
    - Misc. Notes (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Contains miscellaneous notes; sampling data; manuscript, "On the Zermelo Postulate".
    - Misc. Notebooks (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Contains 3 notebooks; notes on physics, mathematics, and chemistry.
    - Misc. Notebooks (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Contains 2 spiral-bound notebooks; notes on Chemistry, French, English, Algebra, ROTC, and Library Science.
    - Philosophy Notes and Coursework, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Contains notes and coursework from an Introduction to Philosophy class at the University of Maryland.
    - English Notes and Essays (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Contains notes and essays from an English class.
  - US Air Force Office of Statistical Control
    - Misc. Stat Control, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Contains "Personal History of Statistical Control in the Army Air Forces" by Brandon Barringer; "Reflections on Combat Operations" by George B. Dantzig; report, "B-24's Losses"; publication, "Sortie & Flying Hour Planning Factors"; "Report of the Commanding General of the Army Air Forces to the Secretary of War"; miscellaneous notes, daily diary, photographs, newspaper clippings, letters, and mementos.
  - Manuscripts
    - Neyman-Pearson 1945, 1941-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Contains drafts, "Contributions to the Neyman-Pearson Fundamental Lemma" by George B. Dantzig; manuscript, "Existence Theorem Pertaining to Neyman-Pearson Lemma, Type A and Similar Regions"; correspondence from the Department of Mathematical Statistics at Columbia University; publication from the International Statistical Conferences, "Sequential Analysis" prepared by Abraham Wald; notes, "Minor Thesis for Doctorate at California"; notes, "Forme Complete du Lemme de Neyman-Pearson".
    - Letter to Civil Service and BLS Papers, 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Contains correspodence to the United States Civil Service Commission; description of duties at the US Bureau of Labor Statistics, Urban Study of Consumer Purchases; resume; manuscript, "A Note on Neyman's Paper dealing with Sampling of Human Populations"; manuscript, "Note on the Lorenz Curve"
    - Dantzig, G.B. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Contains draft and additional notes on SCOOP (Scientific Computation of Optimum Programs).
    - Misc. Papers, 1938-1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Contains miscellaneous manuscripts and notes; topics include the Four Color Theorem, the Neyman-Pearson Unbiased Test of Type A, the Method of Equal Proportions, the Morly Trisector Theorem, and the Bartlett Test.
    - Misc. Stat. Notes of Others (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Contains several manuscripts related to statistics; "Major Problems of the Professional Statistician in the Federal Service"; "Addendum to 'A Study of Racial Bloc Voting in the Territory of Hawaii' by Dorothy Baker" by Dorothy Baker and George Dantzig; "The Method of Inversions as a Test of Significance" by A.C. Rosander; "Statistical Hypotheses and Statistical Tests"; supplement to Jerzy Neyman's "Contribution to the Theory of Sampling Human Populations" by George Dantzig; "An Approach to Problems Involving Disproportionate Frequencies" by Burton D. Seeley; correspondence from the Committee on Professional Statisticians; miscellaneous notes.
    - Lorenz Curve (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Contains draft, "Note on the Lorenz Curve" by George B. Dantzig; notes and graphs.
  - Other
    - Letters, 1934-1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Contains personal correspondence.
    - Bibliographic Information, 1936-1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Contains professional correspondence; job applications; job offers; job descriptions; resumes; academic transcripts.
    - Job Correspondence, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Contains correspondence related to prospective jobs and job offers; notepad.
    - Clippings, 1945-1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Contains miscellaneous clippings of personal interest.
    - Calendars and Notebooks (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Contains calendars detailing personal schedule and two composition notebooks.